export const chapter = "Chapter -7: The World of Food";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
        [
            {
                "question": "Food preservation is the process of treating and handling food to __________ spoilage.",
                "optionA": "accelerate",
                "optionB": "stop or slow down",
                "optionC": "cause",
                "correctAnswer": "stop or slow down"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following techniques involves lowering the temperature to levels unsuitable for microbial growth?",
                "optionA": "Canning",
                "optionB": "Freezing",
                "optionC": "Drying",
                "correctAnswer": "Freezing"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which technique involves cooking fruits or vegetables, sealing them in sterile containers, and boiling the containers to kill bacteria?",
                "optionA": "Vacuum sealing",
                "optionB": "Pasteurization",
                "optionC": "Adding preservatives",
                "correctAnswer": "Canning"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is a natural preservative?",
                "optionA": "Sodium benzoate",
                "optionB": "Oil",
                "optionC": "Pickles",
                "correctAnswer": "Oil"
            },
            {
                "question": "What process involves boiling milk to a high temperature, then suddenly cooling it to extend its shelf life?",
                "optionA": "Fermentation",
                "optionB": "Pasteurization",
                "optionC": "Distillation",
                "correctAnswer": "Pasteurization"
            },
            {
                "question": "What should individuals avoid to prevent food wastage?",
                "optionA": "Cooking food in excess",
                "optionB": "Storing perishable items for a long time",
                "optionC": "Eating according to appetite",
                "correctAnswer": "Cooking food in excess"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is a natural cause of food scarcity?",
                "optionA": "Poverty",
                "optionB": "Floods",
                "optionC": "Government policies",
                "correctAnswer": "Floods"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which man-made cause of food scarcity involves storing food to be sold at a profit?",
                "optionA": "Poverty",
                "optionB": "Natural disasters",
                "optionC": "Hoarding",
                "correctAnswer": "Hoarding"
            },
            {
                "question": "What percentage of the Indian population are tribal people?",
                "optionA": "8%",
                "optionB": "12%",
                "optionC": "15%",
                "correctAnswer": "8%"
            },
            {
                "question": "What type of food has a longer shelf life, grains or vegetables?",
                "optionA": "Grains",
                "optionB": "Vegetables",
                "optionC": "Both have the same shelf life",
                "correctAnswer": "Grains"
            }
        ]
        
    
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
        [
            {
                "question": "Food preservation is the process of treating and handling food to __________ spoilage.",
                "optionA": "accelerate",
                "optionB": "stop",
                "optionC": "reduce",
                "correctAnswer": "stop"
            },
            {
                "question": "__________ foods involves lowering the temperature to levels that make the environment unsuitable for microbial growth.",
                "optionA": "Canning",
                "optionB": "Freezing",
                "optionC": "Drying",
                "correctAnswer": "Freezing"
            },
            {
                "question": "Canning involves cooking fruits or vegetables, sealing them in sterile containers, and boiling the containers to kill or weaken any remaining __________.",
                "optionA": "bacteria",
                "optionB": "yeast",
                "optionC": "mold",
                "correctAnswer": "bacteria"
            },
            {
                "question": "__________ are natural preservatives like oil, salt, and sugar.",
                "optionA": "Sodium benzoate",
                "optionB": "Oil",
                "optionC": "Pickles",
                "correctAnswer": "Oil"
            },
            {
                "question": "Milk is boiled to a high temperature for 10 minutes and then suddenly cooled to a very low temperature in the process of __________.",
                "optionA": "Fermentation",
                "optionB": "Pasteurization",
                "optionC": "Distillation",
                "correctAnswer": "Pasteurization"
            },
            {
                "question": "Individuals should avoid cooking food in excess and storing perishable items for a long time to prevent __________ of food.",
                "optionA": "freshness",
                "optionB": "wastage",
                "optionC": "preservation",
                "correctAnswer": "wastage"
            },
            {
                "question": "Natural causes of food scarcity include droughts, floods, and diseases to the __________.",
                "optionA": "animals",
                "optionB": "crops",
                "optionC": "water sources",
                "correctAnswer": "crops"
            },
            {
                "question": "__________ is a man-made cause of food scarcity where people store food to be sold at a profit.",
                "optionA": "Poverty",
                "optionB": "Natural disasters",
                "optionC": "Hoarding",
                "correctAnswer": "Hoarding"
            },
            {
                "question": "Tribal people form about __________ of the Indian population.",
                "optionA": "5%",
                "optionB": "8%",
                "optionC": "12%",
                "correctAnswer": "8%"
            },
            {
                "question": "__________ have a longer shelf life compared to vegetables.",
                "optionA": "Grains",
                "optionB": "Fruits",
                "optionC": "Meat",
                "correctAnswer": "Grains"
            }
        ]
        
    
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
        [
            {
                "question": "Perishable foods like vegetables, fruits, and bread have a long shelf life.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "False"
            },
            {
                "question": "Food preservation is the process of treating and handling food to accelerate spoilage.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "False"
            },
            {
                "question": "Freezing is a food preservation technique that lowers the temperature to levels unsuitable for microbial growth.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "Canning involves cooking fruits or vegetables, sealing them in sterile containers, and boiling the containers to kill bacteria.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "Vacuum sealing is a technique where preservatives like sodium benzoate are added to food.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "False"
            },
            {
                "question": "Pasteurization involves boiling milk to a high temperature, then suddenly cooling it to extend its shelf life.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "Individuals should avoid cooking food in excess to prevent food wastage.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "Natural causes of food scarcity include poverty and government policies.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "False"
            },
            {
                "question": "Hoarding is a man-made cause of food scarcity where food is stored to be sold at a profit.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "True"
            },
            {
                "question": "Tribal people form about 15% of the Indian population.",
                "optionA": "True",
                "optionB": "False",
                "correctAnswer": "False"
            }
        ]
        
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
